<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Tidy Hippie</title>
  <subtitle>Engineer and admirer of timeless design</subtitle>
  <id>https://tidyhippie.com</id>
  <link href="https://tidyhippie.com"/>
  <link href="https://tidyhippie.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2022-01-06T18:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Brian Littmann</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Turning 34</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tidyhippie.com/turning-34/"/>
    <id>https://tidyhippie.com/turning-34/</id>
    <published>2022-01-06T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T11:46:01-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notable from 2021:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leaving Alo Moves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Road trip to Utah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solo trip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moving to Tulsa with Ariel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pershing roll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I earnestly hope with a cautious optimism that the next year will have a bit more ease. — 1/1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I look back on the year, and even what I wrote in Turning 33, I feel subtly overwhelmed at how much more aligned I feel with myself. In reviewing my notes, I’m not finding seemingly disparate themes, but instead a chain of connected observations that represents a path I’ve long desired to walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent so much time thinking about what I want, often thinking I didn’t know what I want, but in retrospect I think I knew all along. It has just taken some work to actually let myself want it. One aspect of this was admitting I really don’t want much and being at peace with that. Another aspect was letting go of something good to take hold of something better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending over three years in Seattle has felt somewhat like a cocoon. In many ways I am the same person I was years ago, and yet I’ve changed. I believe this will continue to be true, which I find to be beautiful, but this specific moment in my life feels like some sort of metamorphosis of deep alignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I wrote in Turning 32 is still all too applicable, and yet my relationship to all those themes keeps changing. So much desire for control and organization. So much desperation to find the discernment between escapist isolation and true solitude. And that’s the work—continually refining your superpowers. Your addictions are not demons, they are just old friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It feels like I’m changing and also nothing is changing at all. Perhaps this is what spring feels like—waiting to bloom, but nothing is happening yet. — 3/7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unattached desire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can’t hold on to everything good. You must let go of something good to take hold of something new. Unattached desire, but desire nonetheless. — 10/31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire minds that are able to articulate convoluted topics is such a clear way, like painting a scene with language. I’m still digesting the concept of desire, or rather attachment to desire, but here’s what I believe. Desire itself is a lovely thing. It’s a reminder of the inevitable change always happening and a hope for something new, something we might call better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick is to let that desire sit in your open hand without grasping for it. It’s that ephemeral space between not enough and too much, where balance is kept by not being too loose and not being too tight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel this in many ways, one of which is a desire for control of my life—to have my to-dos in order, to have my environment in order, to depend on myself, to eliminate chaos. I needed a release from this, as the suffering it created was evident. If I’m holding too tightly to what I’m already familiar with, how will I grow? How will I find something new? The more I sit with this, the deeper I go into the phrase “Trust the process.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grounded presence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I became very aware of my proclivity to run away, escape, or “fight” the experience of being a human. — 6/12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s wild and quite unfortunate how out of tune many of us are with our intuition. It’s also wild how fantastic it feels when you are aligned with yourself, i.e. following your intuition. But what does the voice of intuition sound like? How do we become aware of what part of us already knows? That requires the practice of presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two areas I’ve become more attuned to over the past couple of years: my need for solitude and my sensitivity to environment. The solitude piece has been a challenge, as discerning when some solitude is needed before it’s too late is often tricky. The environment piece is more fun with room to explore, but the effort for me is centered around that desire for control and knowing when to let go. I’ve also been sensing, for a few years now, a desire to move on from the world of programming. I plan to do something about that by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, being present to intuition is a subset of the practice of presence. Presence, in a traditional sense, is about the here and now. I see it as an inflection point between the internal and external. Grounded presence is aligning your internal world with the experience of the external. To let yourself feel sadness and not dissociate. To let yourself feel pride and not judge others. For me, the practice is to sit with the discomfort and direct my energy with intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transcend and include&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To love people and help them thrive is the most kingly thing I can think of. — 7/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kingly is a word that came to me in a visceral way last year. It’s my personal expression of and desire for equanimity. It’s obvious to me when I’m operating from this space and it’s obvious when I’m not. It’s pure grounded presence—a combination of gratitude, kindness, generosity, and strength. And it feels like a responsibility I’ve been graciously given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of it is not a goal, but a lifelong direction. It’s a continual process of what Ken Wilber calls transcend and include. It looks like growing into maturity while maintaining your sense of play, or learning to admire and adopt certain traits you perhaps once despised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m seeing this play out in my seemingly dominant analytical side. For some time now, Ariel has talked about the concept of emotional boundaries wherein she gets to decide (with practice) when and how she deploys her superpower of feeling what other people are feeling. In December I realized my version of this is setting analytical boundaries with myself. I’m grateful for my inherited trait of analysis, but always operating from that lens is incomplete and can at times be unloving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to switch it off though when I’ve been in it. I struggle to effortlessly transition from one mode to another, but I believe that with awareness, plus practice and patience from all affected, I can wield the blade of analysis well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id="emanate"&gt;Emanate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good friend of mine said he’d rather ask “Who do you want to be?” rather than “What do you want to be?” in the context of growing up. What kind of person do you want to be in the world? How do you want to show up? In reflecting on this, that kingly energy I felt is what I desire to share—to emanate—wherever I go. It’s the confluence of everything previously mentioned: unattached desire, grounded presence, and continual growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my North Star for the year. There is no goal, no failure, no shame to be had in the pursuit of it. It’s simply a reminder of a time when I felt at home with the person I want to keep becoming—myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m not sure we will ever fully know the depths of the beauty of life, but I know that diving deeper into it is continually rewarding, however challenging it may be. — 10/9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Workspaces</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tidyhippie.com/workspaces/"/>
    <id>https://tidyhippie.com/workspaces/</id>
    <published>2021-01-13T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T11:46:01-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  A good workspace is like the anti-depressant you don't have to take.&lt;br&gt;
  It's an homage to your humanity and an incubator of inspiration.&lt;br&gt;
  I've found simplicity to be a good ingredient.&lt;br&gt;
  There is always more to be found.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;div class="postcard"&gt;
  &lt;div class="row"&gt;
    &lt;div class="six columns"&gt;
      &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2006-10-23-DormA.jpg" alt="ViewSonics" /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="six columns"&gt;
      &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2006-10-23-DormB.jpg" alt="ACD20" /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Fanboy. College, October 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="postcard"&gt;
  &lt;div class="row"&gt;
    &lt;div class="six columns"&gt;
      &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2010-07-12-601.jpg" alt="TV Dinner Desk" /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="six columns"&gt;
      &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2011-04-17-AustinA.jpg" alt="PVC Desk" /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The standing desk. 601 and Austin, 2010-2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="postcard"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2011-10-27-GradSchool.jpg" alt="Grad school" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whiteboard. Grad school, October 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="postcard"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2012-08-12-Rockford.jpg" alt="IKEA" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;IKEA. Tulsa studio, August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="postcard"&gt;
  &lt;div class="row"&gt;
    &lt;div class="six columns"&gt;
      &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2012-08-14-NewMedio.jpg" alt="Cinder blocks" /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="six columns"&gt;
      &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2013-06-10-NewMedio.jpg" alt="Spool" /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Spool. New Medio, 2012-2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="postcard"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2016-07-14-NewMedio.jpg" alt="Stool" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stool. New Medio, July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="postcard"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2017-05-27-4334.jpg" alt="Tycho" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tycho. Palindrome, May 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="postcard"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/workspaces/2018-12-19-1925.jpg" alt="Remote" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Remote. Seattle, December 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Turning 33</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tidyhippie.com/turning-33/"/>
    <id>https://tidyhippie.com/turning-33/</id>
    <published>2020-12-31T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T11:46:01-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notable from 2020:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pandemic and quarantine beginning in March&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treehouse trip in May&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;California road trip in August&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transition to Engineering Manager at Alo Moves in August&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long year and I’ve spent more time in my room, or at least my house, than ever before. Somehow it’s felt like there has been nothing to do and yet too much to do, and I earnestly hope with a cautious optimism that the next year will have a bit more ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’ve been slacking as it relates to these annual letters to myself. I still have yet to complete 31 and never started 32. Turning 30 had so much momentum behind it, not to mention space to focus on it, and I was proud of what I wrote. But that turned into a self-imposed pressure to write something for subsequent years that was just as good, so then perfection became the enemy of good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve since reframed or simplified the purpose of these letters of annual reflection. They will serve as bookends for chapters in my life—summaries of what’s been flowing through my head and heart throughout the year without any particular purpose. Maybe one day many years from now I’ll look back on this and smile at my feeble attempts to document and control everything, but be grateful that I made an effort to at least write something down and grow from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find the word and concept of growth fascinating. It’s something capitalism loves, it can imply improvement, or it can simply be understood as an inevitable force of nature coexisting with its counterpart: destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t really force growth, but you can encourage it. I’ve been grateful for the opportunities to grow over the past couple of years, largely as it relates to being in relationship but also my job. I’ve been with my partner for over a year and a half now and we’ve both learned so much about ourselves and each other along the way with all of its ups and downs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we were together, I had a habit of self deprecation and doubt. I doubted my ability to love and would often think of myself as lazy, boring, and apathetic. But having someone so close to you who not only sees who you really are, but tells you what they see and admire and love over and over and over—because it takes hearing it many times—eventually breaks through the walls you’ve built and you are faced with the decision of letting yourself be loved or not. I can assure you the former is much better, albeit sometimes difficult and uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matching my self-awareness with a sense of self-compassion has allowed me to further accept my slower pace of life and care of work, my ability to love and be loved, and ultimately dreading existence less frequently and less intensely. It is good to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be anything else. — Mar 30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id="recurring-themes"&gt;Recurring themes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solitude&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be sent away, to momentarily not exist. That boy still resides there. — May 30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word “alone” came up a lot, though that’s not unique to just this past year. Often, it’s an expression of escape. To not bother and not be bothered—it’s a desire of reprieve, calm, and safety. But this coin of solitude has two sides. One side has been influenced by past traumas, while the other is trying to reframe that narrative and simply seek a sense of restoration. One wants to disappear, the other wants to recharge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distinguishing between these two is something I am still working on. There was a time when perhaps I had too much time alone, but these days I often feel I don’t have enough. I’d like to create some structure for this on a regular basis and do a better job of attuning to moments when I just need to be in my own world for a short while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In a struggle, I managed to say the words “It felt like we were kids.” And it hit us both like a chord struck in such a way that the vibrations of sound penetrate through to something deep within, like tapping into a well of tears long forgotten. — May 30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still often feel a sense of disconnect with my family, and relationships in general, but it no longer feels daunting or hopeless, despite there being lots of work still to do. The theory of relationship is easy to talk about, but when you’re in the thick of it, when you can feel your prefrontal cortex trying to shut down during a moment of conflict, things are difficult. But what makes that rupture worth it is the repair the follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you never experienced much repair? What if you were unknowingly taught to suppress and ignore? Unfortunately, that doesn’t really work and time does not heal all wounds, though it can help numb them. Not only am I still figuring out how to best navigate those situations of rupture when they occur, but also how to approach deeply rooted wounds. It won’t be easy, but again, it is good to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Leaving the store, I said to myself “I feel like going home.” But I don’t know where home is. — Jul 27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homesick isn’t something I think I’ve felt until moving to Seattle. Historically I’ve been fairly close to where I grew up, but now I am many miles away. Beyond leaving what is familiar, which greatly adds to a feeling of comfort and belonging, Tulsa has a much slower pace which I find myself longing for again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s odd to feel displaced, whether relative to a group of people or the city you live in, and usually not in a pleasant way. I don’t feel as though Seattle is home, and yet I also feel I’ve moved on from my original home of Tulsa. So where does this put me? I am still searching for a decision, but do have a desire to be less transient and more invested in a quieter place, ideally close to mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On a board is one of the handful of places I feel most at home with myself. — May 30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id="release"&gt;Release&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve struggled with overthinking for much of my adult life. Not only that, but also a desire for a sense of control over both of my external environment and internal world. I’ve since come to accept that this is not inherently a bad thing, but rather what I’ve been calling my superpower. There are many good things that come from this tendency such as awareness, attention to detail, and a general sense of care. But taken too far, the indecision becomes frustrating and debilitating. This is one of the reasons I enjoy the Pareto principle (80/20 rule) so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, most of my themes from the past four years have been active in nature (focus, groove, engage). As I considered what my theme for 2021 would be coming out of 2020, I realized how much I was craving a sense of repair and rest, regarding both relationships and work. I want to give myself time to recharge through intentional solitude, and during that time I want to let go of this internal pressure to always do more. I want to release, even if for a moment, the thoughts and ideas that never let me rest so that I can come back to them later with presence and power.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Turning 32</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tidyhippie.com/turning-32/"/>
    <id>https://tidyhippie.com/turning-32/</id>
    <published>2020-01-04T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T11:46:01-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notable from 2019:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ariel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transition to Frontend Engineer at Alo Moves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seaside trip in September&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bought a Subaru&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sometimes it takes over a year to finally complete something on my to-do list, which is the case with this annual letter as I finish writing it in January 2021. Better late than never though, as long as it's still important.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I read through last year’s journaling, I wonder what all my friends write about. Do they question themselves? Do they ask about the pain, where it comes from and what to do about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I am a bit obsessed with it, or with myself. I’ve written about—or at least felt—the same things for years now. I’m honestly tired of it. It seems inevitable in a way and I have to accept that. Some days I just have to feel it, but it never lasts forever and I know it will be okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun will rise again and a new day is always right around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id="recurring-themes"&gt;Recurring themes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Love&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I want your presence again as that kiss is fleeting. I have a subtle fear that I will inevitably have moments of escaping, but perhaps that fear is just a sense of shame for what I sometimes need (time to recover). — May 6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year really challenged my belief about my ability to love and be loved. I often feared I would not be "enough" for a relationship, or conversely that I would be "too much" in my particularities and peculiarities. I didn't want to accept that belief and knew the only way it could be challenged was through relationship, and that's exactly what happened starting May 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's uncomfortable being vulnerable because the opposite of that is what used to keep you safe. To downplay myself is just an attempt to protect myself. It's an old friend I've been demonizing without accepting the role it played in a past life. But when your life is different and it's no longer necessary for your survival, it's time to let it go and form new ways of relating. This intimate work can only be done in relationship with someone who is also willing to "touch with love that which was previously touched by fear."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s like this cloud I can’t shake, swinging at something that appears to exist but laughs as I strike nothing. It follows me around, keeping me from seeing clearly, separating me from experience. What is this cloud? Is there even a cloud at all? — Jun 18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a sense of safety and calm I find through organization. It's a form of relative certitude, but only insofar as it means I don't have to "think" about it anymore because I've thoroughly thought it through to a conclusion. But when you approach an idea infinitely more slippery than a peeled mango in an attempt to distill it into a single thing, it will perpetually elude you. It’s like chasing your own tail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like curating the tangibles in my life (new car, new clothes), I try to curate existence itself. Much like these annual letters, I try to attain final contentment through perpetual refinement, but perhaps there is never a destination or "arriving", perhaps it is always a game and always changing. The only constant is my state of mind, my perspective, my being present to the here and now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I just want to make simple things. Is there room for that in this world? — Feb 20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplicity can be found somewhere between too much and not enough. It's where you arrive after overthinking and then thinking a little bit more. Once found, it doesn't ask anything of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I crave simplicity as a means of control and to ease my mind. I seem to find it through intention, but only after mistaking it for perfection. It is my balm to the shame I carry around ambition, for I do not think of myself as an ambitious person in a society that can't seem to get enough. I want to embrace a simple life that minimizes stress, as I create enough of that on my own (low key, high maintenance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id="attune"&gt;Attune&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often struggle to know what I want. Perhaps I avoid it because I turn it into an absolute and put way too much pressure on making any decision, big or small. Or I push myself to "do more" when that might not actually be what I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes I do know what I want, as indicated by the things I continually write about so much: low key city, low stress job, group of friends to adventure with, etc. I also know that I need regular doses of alone time to recharge, though discerning exactly when can be tricky. The same is true for catching myself overthinking. That's where attuning comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to check in with yourself to see what your intuition is saying. Do you actually want more Pad Thai or are you stuffed? Do you actually have the emotional space and energy to socialize or are you drained? Do you still need to do more research or are you stuck spinning your wheels having already blown past the helpful twenty percent of effort that gets you eighty percent of a decision?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are great questions to ask, but awareness is only half of the equation. Attune, then act.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Turning 31: Surfing in Solitude</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tidyhippie.com/turning-31/"/>
    <id>https://tidyhippie.com/turning-31/</id>
    <published>2019-01-04T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T11:46:01-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notable from 2018:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Left New Medio to take a year off&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iceland and Amsterdam with friends in April&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copenhagen and Stockholm by myself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moved to Seattle via a six-week summer road trip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joined Alo Moves in December&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two years after setting out to write this second annual letter to myself, I am just now finishing it at the beginning of 2021. It was close to done, but ironically enough I let the very thing I was trying to write about get in the way. There was a lot I wanted to communicate given so much change for me in 2018 and I got stuck overthinking yet again. It may not be as cohesive as I’d like, but let’s allow it to be good enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago I wrote a letter that I claimed to be to myself and for myself, but that letter longed to be published so there's been a slight change of plans. I'm still writing for myself, but it shall be as though I'm speaking from this stage of sorts to myself sitting out there in the audience next to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so what else has changed since then? A lot and nothing at all. I left the country, came back, moved across the country on a six-week road trip and have landed in Seattle. My hiatus from web development is also over, and for the record, software engineering interviews are weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past that, I've managed to bring along all the same habits I had in Tulsa, which isn't surprising. And although they didn't take up in room in the car while packing, their weight is just as heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id="forgo-comfort-to-find-your-groove"&gt;Forgo comfort to find your groove.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year around this time, I would spend my mornings at a coffee shop in Tulsa sipping slowly and typing even slower as I distilled many years of thoughts into not-so-novel philosophies. Turning the corner of 30, this great millennial urge was bubbling up to positively disrupt my life and perhaps finally pursue some things I had merely made lists about for the past decade. And I did—at least to a degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, approximately 2,000 miles away from that coffee shop, I sit looking out at the Olympic mountains just beyond a Puget Sound still asleep under a blanket of fog from a place I now call home. But getting here wasn't easy for me. Remember Resistance? That thing which opposes any and all of your creative acts and motions to improve? Well it goes by another name, comfort, and that's not something I had much of in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dallas → Reykjavik&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can escape other people, but I can't escape myself. — April 12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iceland is so beautiful and surreal it can mess with your mind. It's another world that feels like fantasy as you wade through the bluest waters and scramble across the blackest sands. Waterfalls are as common as creeks and you'll feel every drop of rain in the wind hit you like a thought from your subconscious you'd rather not acknowledge. And yet you'll want more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This of course is compounded by spending every waking hour with the same three friends you're traveling with. So when you're in the car for hours at a time unnecessarily pondering your impact on social dynamics, the pressure will continue to build as you keep seeking a false escape in the solitude of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amsterdam → Copenhagen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sometimes it feels like my brain is unraveling, like a spool of yarn. — April 26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was therefore somewhat ironic to desire being alone yet also have huge separation anxiety as I parted ways with my friends at the Schipol airport terminal in Amsterdam. Now with an ocean between myself and everyone I know, I lie in bed wondering what the hell I'm doing and laugh at my intent to put myself in this exact situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stockholm → New York City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There was nothing left to do but crumble and cry in utter weakness. — May 6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, I watched Lion and Human Flow on the flights back home. If you care about people at all, those films will probably get you too. But that's not exactly what my crumbling like a scone was all about. It was the weight of unknowing that broke me. Unknowing of every "Why?" you could possibly ask that, if you are so brave and humble to admit you cannot be certain, will leave you with an incredible sense of lostness. Moments like this are the valleys at the bottom of peaks you've been on top of before and will return to again—valleys that present you with a blank canvas prepared for any story of beauty you wish to paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tulsa → Seattle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I got my ass kicked, but at least I got in the water. — June 26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never have I felt more imprisoned inside my own mind than on the day before I said goodbye to Tulsa. What can fit in my car and what do I leave behind? Oh but I don't want to leave these things behind! And I don't want to leave my friends and my home behind. What if I just don't leave? What if all I'm really doing is running away? It's comfortable here, but I know if I don't go the pain of regret will soon be greater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after one last beer with friends, I left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for the next six weeks I wouldn't know where I'd be sleeping more than a week in advance. From frosty mornings in Telluride to dreaming in the deserts of California, I camped my way out of a climate-controlled bubble into something that never let my mind wander for too long because my whole being was doing the wandering instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="a-groovy-story"&gt;A groovy story&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest Resistance-defeating moments happened on this road trip. I had been considering buying a drone for some time, and literally walked into a Best Buy in Denver at the beginning of my trip to do so but for one dumb reason or another walked out empty handed. It wasn't until I was driving through Monument Valley that the potency of this mistake made itself known. Anger turned inward with a breath, exhaling resolve to make amends for my creative sins, I desperately longed to capture the beauty of this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I bought a drone in Flagstaff. After visiting my cousin in Prescott, I drove over four hours back to those natural monoliths to capture their essence from the sky as the sun set. Unfortunately I underestimed their size and wasn’t quite able to realize the vision I had (I wanted to fly over the tops), but it still felt good to have an idea and execute. It felt like the beginning of a creative block being overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-pursuit-of-potential-is-a-painful-paradox"&gt;The pursuit of potential is a painful paradox.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The core of my overthinking may imply a sense of care. Care to find the best possible answer or solution, and exhausting all the options in order to find it—like solving a maze. But in the end, perfection can’t be found. There is no center to this maze. — Feb 22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nature of asking a question is a very curious thing—both in our ability to even do so as well as the effect it has in revealing a potential hole in our knowledge that we may or may not be able to fill. This curiosity is innately human, the root of science, and precariously problematic when it comes to probing at matters unseen and unheard—matters felt only deep within ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it's not actually the asking of a question that is problematic, it's the desire and demand of an answer. To make certain that which is unknown is a dangerous thing, as observed by many of the horrors in our history. Therefore, as I don't believe we have a right to certitude, this leaves us with an uncomfortable tension of not knowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, while your cosmic curiosities are fertile ground for this tension, how it applies at an individual level—that is, who am I and what am I going to do—becomes both liberating and crippling. It begins with feeling as though who you are or what you're doing isn't "meaningful", that you're just existing, directionless and drifting. Then you remember there is no bound to meaninglessness and receive a momentary liberation from "being somebody" as you resolve to accept where you are and improve where you're going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But alas, meaningfulness has no bound either. You can never do enough. As you perpetually chase the carrot of unfulfilled potential all the way into the hands of death, you will leave this world with a thousand stones unturned, and still a thousand more unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then, what lies between not doing anything and not doing everything? Well, I propose simply doing something. That is the key to making progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="an-indecisive-aside"&gt;An indecisive aside&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that I strive for a sense of perfection or certitude in knowing what I want, both as it relates to tangible decisions such as which lamp to get or life decisions such as which job to take. At first it feels noble and intentional, but it quickly devolves into overthinking and indecision which in turn leads to a restless anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to reflect on this tendency of mine, and I’ve come to realize that my greatest gift and greatest weakness are the same. I move slowly and observantly. I try to think my way through a lot of things, but am beginning to think I should lean more on my intuition to make the final decision. Usually I’m deciding between two good options anyway and ultimately I’d rather move on and enjoy either decision rather than languish in being stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Ego’s Fear: If I stop this strategy, if I stop figuring out what I need to do, the ‘ground’ will not be there to support me. The world cannot be trusted—without my mental activity I will be left vulnerable. Everything will fall to pieces—I will fall and be lost. If my mind does not keep ‘swimming’, I will sink.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;hr /&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Wisdom of the Enneagram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id="to-engage-is-greater-than-escape"&gt;To engage is greater than escape.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Does compassion exist without action? — Jan 9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One night long ago during my college days I was lying in bed at my parents' house listening to an As Cities Burn album on my click wheel iPod. On that album is a song that voiced something I've long felt guilty for and still struggle to redeem. It goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All the love I want to give gets caught between every rib.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;What does that make me?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I have good intentions but no exit for them to come out right through.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I'm in the wrong body. I must have stumbled in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For someone who spends a lot of time in the rabbit holes of his mind, I think about other people a lot. And yet I remain at what feels like miles away from belonging. Much of this is self-imposed, as I often let my neurotic tendencies drive me into isolation. I don’t want to exacerbate any feelings of misfit-ness, I don’t want to feel annoyed by things no one else notices, and honestly sometimes I’m simply disinterested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we lose our built-in community, whether found in family or neighborhood, we must compensate. I've found this to be a difficult thing. To keep up with friends living in another state, to make plans with people busy with their own lives, to establish new friendships through common interests—it feels like a full-time job. It's much easier to distract myself with ridiculous theories and wishful projects, but even productivity won't satiate this desire for connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems we as a culture (and I am probably projecting here) are feeling increasingly alone. No wonder there has been such a boom in the world of self-help. But in the end, I don't think self-help is really about the self at all. Perhaps we should be helping each other instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To go in the dark with a light is to know light.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To know the dark, go dark. Go without sight,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And find that the dark, too, blooms and sings,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And is traveled by dark feet and dark wings.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;hr /&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wendell Berry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Portfolio (2018)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tidyhippie.com/portfolio-2018/"/>
    <id>https://tidyhippie.com/portfolio-2018/</id>
    <published>2018-08-09T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T11:46:01-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Things of quality&lt;br&gt;have no fear of time.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a shirt with those words printed on the back. It reminds me of the fulfillment found in choosing the hard work of doing what's right. But perfection is an illusory attainment and I think the reprieve of balance comes when we simply focus on improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to philosophical quests, I've been working across the whole stack since 2012 building out the back and front ends of web-based desktop and mobile apps. On a given day I'd like to have asked clients the right questions, written timeless documentation, and made a few pixels happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's take a look at some of my work below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href="mailto:brian.littmann@gmail.com" class="outline-btn"&gt;Let's Talk&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h3 class="project-header"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/portfolio_2018/newmedio.png" alt="New Medio logo" height="45px" /&gt; New Medio
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  New Medio is where I spent the past six years as the lead developer building custom applications for a number of different clients. Some of these projects were internal company tools while others were consumer facing. Let's start with the former.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wine and spirits broker approached us asking for an overhaul of their spreadsheet-based purchase order and invoicing system. After many meetings digesting the business logic and tax reporting requirements, I built and delivered the internal Rails application that helps power their business averaging over $6 million in annual billings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/portfolio_2018/screens/select.png" alt="Purchase order system" class="screenshot" /&gt;

&lt;p class="project-details"&gt;Another internal application, this oil and gas company brought us detailed wireframes for a job dispatching application that would interface with an existing MySQL database and require cross-domain single sign-on functionality. I built out the Django-based web app with job management, drag and drop scheduling, and helped scale the system upon reaching bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/portfolio_2018/screens/dispatch.png" alt="Job dispatcher" class="screenshot" /&gt;

&lt;p class="project-details"&gt;On one of our larger and more collaborative projects, the client wanted to create a new public-facing event registration platform that would eventually reach monthly revenues in excess of $1 million. We worked closely with their event coordinators and accounting teams to create the registration flows and meet reporting requirements, then progressively grew the platform by deploying many ancillary features such as event day tools, mobile ticketing, order adjustments, and comprehensive event management for company admins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/portfolio_2018/screens/eventelf.png" alt="Event registration" class="screenshot" /&gt;

&lt;h3 class="project-header"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/portfolio_2018/podium.png" alt="Podium Skate logo" height="40px" /&gt; Podium Skate
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Podium is breaking ground in the skateboarding scene, providing a way for skaters around the world to compete against each other and earn points that could get them invited to national competitions.
  At its core, skaters upload their clips and enter them into competitions, which are scored by the community. Finalists are then judged by a panel of pro skaters.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I designed and built the fully tested and documented Rails API including asynchronous video uploading and encoding through AWS, admin and competition judging areas, and was the lead developer for the Ionic 2 based iOS and Android apps.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/portfolio_2018/screens/podium.png" alt="Podium Skate project" class="screenshot" /&gt;

&lt;h3 class="project-header"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/portfolio_2018/root.png" alt="Root Tulsa logo" height="35px" /&gt; Root Tulsa
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Root Tulsa is an interconnected geolocation CMS that serves as a guide to life in Tulsa for both locals and visitors featuring places and events nearby.
  Working with the client to refine the initial vision, we started with a native iOS app backed by a Rails API along with a mobile web frontend.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I was the lead architect and developer for the API backend, original mobile web app, and admin CMS. Many revisions to the app were made, including support for recurring events, and the project has continued to evolve since my last involvement.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/portfolio_2018/screens/root.png" alt="Root Tulsa project" class="screenshot" /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
